那么，我知道我们需要创建布局，
So, we know we need to create layouts
并为不同尺寸和像素的屏幕优化资源。
and assets optimized for different screen pixel densities
现在就是个很好的时机，
and sizes. So, now's a great time to
向你介绍Android的框架资源。
introduce you to the Android resource framework. All externalized
所以的Android外部资源，包括字符串布局、绘制区、动画
Android resources, everything from strings to layouts to
都储存在你项目的res文件夹中。
drawables and animations are all stored within your project's
你将你的字符串资源放在strings.xml文件中，
res folder. You've already been putting your strings
该文件储存在值文件夹中。
in the strings.xml file stored in the values folder.
同样，你将你的布局存在布局文件夹中。
And you've been putting your layouts into the layout
当你引用你的资源时，
folder. And you know to reference your resources using
需要在XML文件和调用代码中标识出来。
at notation within both your xml or within the
这样在程序运行的时候，Android才会给程序分配适当的资源。
code. And then at runtime, Android will insert the
目前，一切都很顺利。
appropriate resource for you. So far, so good. And
到这，情况会变得有意思一点。
here's where things get a little more interesting. Android
Android允许为每一个资源创建替代版本，
allows you to create alternative versions of every resource
并允许它们被放置在不同的文件夹中。
by placing them into folders with different qualifiers. We separate
我们用连字符区分这个使用的资源。
each of those using a hyphen. And we can
我们可以基于任何事物，从语言或者方言
add those qualifiers based on anything from language and
到设备是否置入插槽中，
or dialect to whether the device is docked, the
以及触摸屏类型，显示器像素密度，
type of touch screen, the pixel density of the
屏幕方向，
display, the orientation of the screen, and most importantly
还有对响应式设计尤其重要的，这一
for a responsive design in particular, the smallest available
布局所能支持的最小屏幕宽度。
screen width which you can support with that layout.
程序运行时，Android会检查当前设备配置，
At runtime, Android will check the current device configuration,
count
语言，屏幕尺寸，像素大小，等等，
it's language, it's screen size, pixel density, everything,
然后再依此加载相应的布局，字符串以及绘制屏幕。
and then load the right layout strings and drawables
你甚至可以将这些限定词链接在一起。
accordingly. You can even chain these qualifiers together. For
例如，针对德语用户创建一个不同的布局，
example, to create a different layout for German language
就要考虑到有些真的很长的德语单词，
users to account for all of those really long
或更典型的，针对特定屏幕尺寸和设备配置的组合。
German words, or more typically for a combination of
现在，请记住，
screen size and device configuration. Now, keep in mind
下面的这些值都是可以在运行的时候更改的。
that many of these values can change at runtime.
最常见的更改就是长宽的拉伸。
The most common change being that of orientation. And
也就是这个原因，每当设备配置被更改的时候，
it's for this reason that Android activities are destroyed
Android activities 都要被破坏并重新创建。
and recreated whenever the device configuration changes. And that's
这是因为诸如屏幕方向改变这样简单的事情，
because the layout and all of the resources within it
就会导致布局和资源分配出现完全不同的情况。
could be completely different based on something as simple
现在，有了这样一种机制，
as screen orientation change. Now it's good practice, as
你可以很好的本地化你的应用，
well, to localize your apps and provide translated strings
并为你所有的用户提供翻译好的字符串。
for all of your users using this mechanism. And that's
这样就成了一个很简单的任务了。
a task made a lot easier. Thanks to Google
感谢Google Play Publisher站点提供这样的服务。
Play Publisher site that can offer you this service. It's
为不同的像素分辨率提供不同的可绘制区域，
also a really good idea to provide different drawables
同样是一个好主意，
at the appropriate pixel density, so you can get a
这样你就可以在每个设备上都得到清晰美观的照片。
nice crisp image on every device. And when it
当它开始涉及到可选择布局时，Android已经完成了几个可替代模型了。
comes to providing alternative layouts, Android has gone through a
在初期，
few alternative models. Starting in the early days, with this
有几个选择是，小屏，大屏，超大屏。
screen buckets idea of small, normal large, and extra large.
但自从Android 3.2开始，新提供的最小宽度限定词
But, since Android 3.2, the new smallest width qualifier has
使得我们能更好的的控制我们的布局。
given us much more fine grain control over our layouts.